I want to tell you the story
سأخبركم بقصتي
about the time I almost got kidnapped
حول المرّة التي كدت فيها أن أُختطف
in the trunk of a red Mazda Miata.
داخل صندوق سيارة "مازدا مياتا" حمراء اللون
It's the day after graduating from design school
حدث ذلك بعد تخرجي من كلية التصميم
and I'm having a yard sale.
حين كنت أعرض بعض أغراضي القديمة للبيع
And this guy pulls up in this red Mazda
فجأةً، ظهر رجل قد أوقف سيارته المازدا الحمراء
and he starts looking through my stuff.
وبدا كأنه يبحث عن شيء ما بين معروضاتي
And he buys a piece of art that I made.
ثم قام بشراء واحدة من أعمالي الفنية
And it turns out he's alone in town for the night,
وقد اتّضح أنه وحيد في البلدة الليلة
driving cross-country on a road trip
يقود سيارته في رحلة عبر البلاد
before he goes into the Peace Corps.
قبل ذهابه إلى "بيس كوربس" -وكالة تطوعية-
So I invite him out for a beer
لذا قمت بدعوته لنحتسي مشروبًا
and he tells me all about his passion
و قام بإخباري عن شغفه
for making a difference in the world.
ليكون عنصرًا مؤثرًا في هذا العالم
Now it's starting to get late,
سرعان ما بدأ الوقت يتأخر
and I'm getting pretty tired.
و سرعان ما شعرت بالتعب
As I motion for the tab,
وبينما كنت أشير للنادل ليجلب لي فاتورتي
I make the mistake of asking him,
اقترفت خطأً حينما سألته:
"So where are you staying tonight?"
"إذاً.. أين ستنام الليلة؟"
And he makes it worse by saying,
و لعل ما جعل الأمر أسوأ بالنسبة لي
"Actually, I don't have a place."
إجابته البريئة: "صراحةً، ليس لدي مكان أنام فيه!"
And I'm thinking, "Oh, man!"
بدأت هنا أكلّم نفسي: "يا.. رجل!"
What do you do?
"ما التصرف الصحيح في موقف كهذا؟"
We've all been there, right?
جميعنا مررنا بأوقات كهذه، أليس كذلك؟
Do I offer to host this guy?
"هل أستضيف هذا الرجل؟"
But, I just met him -- I mean,
"لكنني لم أعرفه إلا لبضع ساعات"
he says he's going to the Peace Corps,
"أعني، إدعاؤه الذهاب إلى وكالة تطوعية"
but I don't really know if he's going to the Peace Corps
"ما الذي يضمن لي أنه إدّعاء صادق!!"
So then I hear myself saying,
لم يمض الكثير قبل أن أخبره لا إراديّاً:
"Hey, I have an airbed you can stay on in my living room."
"لديّ سريرٌ هوائيّ وبعض المساحة، يمكنك النوم عندي الليلة"
And the voice in my head goes,
وانطلق هنا صوت يوبّخني في رأسي:
"Wait, what?"
"ماذا فعلت للتو!"
That night, I'm laying in bed,
وطوال تلك الليلة كنت مستلقياً على السرير
I'm staring at the ceiling and thinking,
أنظر الى السقف وأفكّر:
"Oh my god, what have I done?
"يا إلهي، لمَ فعلت هذا؟"
There's a complete stranger sleeping in my living room.
"هناك رجلٌ غريبٌ ينام في غرفة معيشتي!"
What if he's psychotic?"
"ماذا إن كان مختلًا عقليًّا؟"
My anxiety grows so much,
كان قلقي يتصاعد كل ثانية،
I leap out of bed,
قفزت من السرير،
I sneak on my tiptoes to the door,
تسللّت بأطراف أصابعي إلى الباب،
and I lock the bedroom door.
وأقفلت باب الغرفة!
It turns out he was not psychotic.
اتّضح في النهاية أنه لم يكن مختلًا.
We've kept in touch ever since.
و قد أصبحنا صديقين منذ ذلك الحين
And the piece of art he bought at the yard sale
أما اللوحات التي أشتراها منّي
is hanging in his classroom; he's a teacher now.
فهي معلّقة الآن في غرفة الصف خاصّته؛ فقد أصبح مدرّساً.
This was my first hosting experience,
كانت هذه أول تجربة استضافة أقوم بها،
and it completely changed my perspective.
وقد غيّرت وجهة نظري تمامًا.
Maybe the people that my childhood taught me to label as strangers
ربما، ذات الأشخاص الذين اعتدت منذ طفولتي أن أدعوهم بالغرباء
were actually friends waiting to be discovered.
لَيْسوا سوى أصدقاءٍ لم أحظَ بعدُ بصداقتهم.
The idea of hosting people on airbeds gradually became natural to me
شيئاً فشيئاً، أصبح من الطبيعي لي أن أستضيف الأشخاص في منزلي
and when I moved to San Francisco,
وعندما انتقلت إلى سان فرانسيسكو،
I brought the airbed with me.
أحضرت معي السرير الهوائي.
So now it's two years later.
سننتقل الآن إلى ما حصل بعد سنتين
I'm unemployed, I'm almost broke,
كنت عاطلاً عن العمل، ومفلساً تقريباً
my roommate moves out, and then the rent goes up.
انتقل شركائي في السكن، و لم يعد بإمكاني تغطية الأجرة
And then I learn there's a design conference coming to town,
علمت آنذاك، بوجود مؤتمر للتصميم في البلدة قريباً
and all the hotels are sold out.
وبأنّه لم يبقَ غرف شاغرة في الفنادق.
And I've always believed that turning fear into fun
ولطالما آمنت بأن تحويل المخيف إلى ممتع
is the gift of creativity.
هو ما يدعى بالإبداع.
So here's what I pitch my best friend and my new roommate Brian Chesky:
إذاً، هذا ما عرضته على صديقي المفضل وشريكي في السكن "بريان تشيسكي":
"Brian, thought of a way to make a few bucks --
"بريان، خطرت لي طريقة لربح بعض الدولارات
turning our place into 'designers bed and breakfast,'
لنحوّل مسكننا إلى "مأوى و مأكل المصممين"
offering young designers who come to town a place to crash,
نتيح للمصممين الشبان القادمين إلى البلدة مكاناً ليناموا فيه
complete with wireless Internet, a small desk space,
مكان مزوّد بخدمة إنترنت ومكان لمكتب صغير،
sleeping mat, and breakfast each morning.
وسريرٍ بسيط، وفطورُ في كلّ صباح.
Ha!"
ها!"
We built a basic website and Airbed and Breakfast was born.
صممّنا موقعاً متواضعاً على الإنترنت، وهكذا تأسس "سرير وفطور"
Three lucky guests got to stay
و هكذا حظي ثلاثة نزلاءٍ بفرصة رائعة
on a 20-dollar airbed on the hardwood floor.
للإقامة على سريرٍ من نوعية العشرين دولاراً على أرض خشبية.
But they loved it, and so did we.
لكنّهم أعجبوا بذلك! ونحن أيضاً.
I swear, the ham and Swiss cheese omelets we made
أؤكد لكم بأن مذاق اللحم والبيض الذي حضّرناه للضيوف
tasted totally different because we made them for our guests.
اختلف تماماً عمًّ اعتدناه، فقط لأنه كان للضيوف.
We took them on adventures around the city,
اصطحبناهم في رحلة حول المدينة.
and when we said goodbye to the last guest,
وحينما كنا نودع آخر ضيف
the door latch clicked,
بعد توديع الضيف الأخير بينهم،
Brian and I just stared at each other.
ارتسمت علامات الدهشة على وجهينا أنا وبريان
Did we just discover it was possible to make friends
هل اكتشفنا للتوّ بأنّه من الممكن كسب الأصدقاء
while also making rent?
أثناء عملك لكسب إيجار المنزل؟
The wheels had started to turn.
و هكذا بدأت أمورنا بالعمل.
My old roommate, Nate Blecharczyk,
شريك غرفتي القديم "نيت بليتشارزك"،
joined as engineering co-founder.
أنضم بصفته شريكاً مؤسساً في مجال الهندسة.
And we buckled down to see
وفكرنا بجديّة فيما إذا كان ممكناً
if we could turn this into a business.
تحويل الأمر إلى عمل حقيقيّ.
Here's what we pitched investors:
إليكم ما عرضناه حينها على المستثمرين:
"We want to build a website
"سنصمم موقعاً على الإنترنت
where people publicly post pictures of their most intimate spaces,
حيث يستطيع الناس أن ينشروا صوراً لأكثر الأماكن أُلفةً لهم في منازلهم
their bedrooms, the bathrooms --
غرف نومهم، مراحيضهم!
the kinds of rooms you usually keep closed when people come over.
تلك الغرف التي عادةّ ما نغلق أبوابها عند قدوم الضيوف.
And then, over the Internet,
وبعدها، وعبر الإنترنت
they're going to invite complete strangers to come sleep in their homes.
سيقومون بعرض منازلهم لاستقبال ضيوفٍ غرباء، مقابل المال.
It's going to be huge!"
سيكون مشروعاً ضخماً!"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We sat back, and we waited for the rocket ship to blast off.
جلسنا وانتظرنا ريثما تثمر الفكرة ذهباً
It did not.
ولكنها لم تثمر شيئاً.
No one in their right minds would invest in a service
لم يرغب أيّ شخصٍ ذو عقل سليم بالاستثمار في فكرة
that allows strangers to sleep in people's homes.
تسمح بإقامة الغرباء في منازل الناس.
Why?
لماذا؟
Because we've all been taught as kids, strangers equal danger.
لأننا تعلمنا منذ الطفولة بأنّ الشخص الغريب، هو شخص مؤذٍ
Now, when you're faced with a problem, you fall back on what you know,
حسناً، حينما يواجه أحدنا مشكلةً ما سيحاول الاعتماد على معلوماته لحلّها
and all we really knew was design.
وكلّ ما كان لدينا من علمٍ هو التصميم.
In art school, you learn that design is much more
في كليّة التصميم تتعلّم بأن التصميم هو أكثر من مجرّد
than the look and feel of something -- it's the whole experience.
المظهر الخارجيّ المتعلق بشيء ما، بل يتعلق بكامل تفاصيل التجربة.
We learned to do that for objects,
تعلّمنا تطبيق ذلك على أشياء ملموسة
but here, we were aiming to build Olympic trust
ولكن هنا، كنا نهدف إلى بناء ثقة حقيقيّة
between people who had never met.
بين أشخاصٍ لم يسبق لهم التعارف.
Could design make that happen?
هل يمكن للتصميم أن يفعل ذلك؟
Is it possible to design for trust?
هل من الممكن تصميم شيء، يُكسِبُ الثقة؟
I want to give you a sense of the flavor of trust
سأحاول الآن أن أفعل شيئاً، يشعركم بنكهة الثقة
that we were aiming to achieve.
التي كنا نحاول تحقيقها.
I've got a 30-second experiment
سنقوم الآن بتجربة مدّتها 30 ثانية
that will push you past your comfort zone.
لإخراجكم قليلاً ممَّ اعتدتم عليه.
If you're up for it, give me a thumbs-up.
إن كنتم مستعدّين، ارفعوا إبهامكم للأعلى.
OK, I need you to take out your phones.
ممتاز، أريد منكم إخراج هواتفكم
Now that you have your phone out,
وبعد إخراجها،
I'd like you to unlock your phone.
من فضلكم، افتحوا أقفال هواتفكم
Now hand your unlocked phone to the person on your left.
و ليعطِ كلّ منكم هاتفه غير المقفل إلى الشخص الجالس على يساره.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
That tiny sense of panic you're feeling right now --
هذا الشعور الضئيل بالخوف الذي يشعر به كلّ منكم الآن
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
is exactly how hosts feel the first time they open their home.
هو بالضبط ما يشعر به المضيف عند فتح بيته للمرة الأولى.
Because the only thing more personal than your phone
لأن الشيء الوحيد الأكثر خصوصيّة من هواتفكم
is your home.
هو منازلكم!
People don't just see your messages,
لن يري الناس رسائلكم فقط
they see your bedroom,
بل سَيرَوْن غرف نومكم،
your kitchen, your toilet.
مطابخكم، و مراحيضكم.
Now, how does it feel holding someone's unlocked phone?
والآن، كيف تشعرون إزاء حمل هاتفٍ غير مقفل لشخص لا تعرفونه؟
Most of us feel really responsible.
أغلبيتنا حقا يشعرون بالمسؤولية.
That's how most guests feel when they stay in a home.
وهذا ما يشعر به معظم الضيوف عند الإقامة في منزل ما.
And it's because of this that our company can even exist.
ولهذا السبب، استطاعت شركتنا أن تُبصر النور.
By the way, who's holding Al Gore's phone?
بالمناسبة، من يحمل هاتف "آل غور"؟ -سياسي أميركي سابق-
Would you tell Twitter he's running for President?
هلّا كتبت عبر حساب التويتر خاصته، أنّه سيترشّح للرئاسة؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
OK, you can hand your phones back now.
حسناً يمكنكم إعادة الهواتف الآن.
So now that you've experienced the kind of trust challenge
والآن، بعد أن جرّبتم جزءاً من تحدّي الثقة
we were facing,
الذي كنّا نواجهه،
I'd love to share a few discoveries we've made along the way.
سأطلعكم على ما اكتشفناه في طريقنا بهذا الخصوص.
What if we changed one small thing
ماذا لو غيرنا شيئاً واحدًا صغيراً
about the design of that experiment?
حول تصميم تلك التجربة؟
What if your neighbor had introduced themselves first, with their name,
ماذا عن جارك إذا قدّم نفسه أولًا واسمه،
where they're from, the name of their kids or their dog?
من أين هم، أسماء أطفالهم أو كلبهم؟
Imagine that they had 150 reviews of people saying,
تخيل لو توافرت عنهم 150 ملاحظة من كلام الناس،
"They're great at holding unlocked phones!"
"إنهم رائعون في حمل هواتف غير مقفلة!"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now how would you feel about handing your phone over?
الأن ماذا تشعر عند إعارة هاتفك؟
It turns out,
اتضح،
a well-designed reputation system is key for building trust.
نظام حسن السمعة هو مفتاح بناء الثقة.
And we didn't actually get it right the first time.
وفي الحقيقة لم نتلقاها صحيحة في أول مرة.
It's hard for people to leave bad reviews.
إنه أمر صعب بالنسبة للناس أن يتركوا انطباعاً سلبياً.
Eventually, we learned to wait until both guests and hosts
وفي النهاية، تعلمنا الانتظار حتى يترك الضيوف والمضيفين
left the review before we reveal them.
انطباعاتهم قبل أن نكشفها ،
Now, here's a discovery we made just last week.
الأن هذا اكتشاف صنعناه الأسبوع الماضي.
We did a joint study with Stanford,
أجرينا دراسة مشتركة مع جامعة ستانفورد،
where we looked at people's willingness to trust someone
حيث بحثنا عن الأشخاص الذين سنستمد ثقتهم
based on how similar they are in age, location and geography.
بناءاً على مدى التشابه في السن والموقع الجغرافي.
The research showed, not surprisingly,
الباحثون أظهروا، بأنه ليس من المستغرب،
we prefer people who are like us.
بأننا نفضل الأشخاص الذين أعجبوا بنا.
The more different somebody is,
الشيء المختلف جدًا هو،
the less we trust them.
نثق فيهم بشكل منخفض.
Now, that's a natural social bias.
الأن هذا هو التحيّز الإجتماعي الطبيعيّ.
But what's interesting is what happens
لكن المثير للاهتمام هو ما يحدث
when you add reputation into the mix,
عندما تضيف السمعة في هذا المزيج،
in this case, with reviews.
في هذه الحالة، مع الانطباعات.
Now, if you've got less than three reviews,
الأن، إذا كان لديك أقل من 3 انطباعات،
nothing changes.
لن يتغير شيء.
But if you've got more than 10,
إذا كان لديك أكثر من 10،
everything changes.
كل شيء سيختلف.
High reputation beats high similarity.
السمعة العالية تتغلب على التشابه الكبير.
The right design can actually help us overcome
التصميم الجيد يستطيع فعلاً مساعدتنا للتغلب علي
one of our most deeply rooted biases.
واحدة من أكثر تحيزاتنا تجذرًا.
Now we also learned that building the right amount of trust
الأن تعلمنا إيضًا أن بناء الثقة الصحيحة
takes the right amount of disclosure.
تتخذ كمية مناسبة من الكشف.
This is what happens when a guest first messages a host.
هذا ما يحدث عندما يتكلم ضيف إلى مضيف.
If you share too little, like, "Yo,"
إذا تكلمت قليلاً، مثل، "يو"
acceptance rates go down.
معدلات القبول تنخفض.
And if you share too much, like,
وإذا تكلمت كثيرًا، مثل
"I'm having issues with my mother,"
"أعاني مشاكل مع أمي،"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
acceptance rates also go down.
معدلات القبول تنخفض.
But there's a zone that's just right,
لكن يوجد منطقة وحيدة على حق،
like, "Love the artwork in your place. Coming for vacation with my family."
مثل، "أحب تلك الأعمال الفنية لديك. قادم لقضاء عطلة مع عائلتي."
So how do we design for just the right amount of disclosure?
إذًا كيف نصمم فقط البناء الصحيح للإستكشاف؟
We use the size of the box to suggest the right length,
نحن نستخدم حجم الصندوق لنقترح الطول المناسب،
and we guide them with prompts to encourage sharing.
ونحن نوجههم لنشجعهم على التشارك.
We bet our whole company
نحن نراهن على كل الشركة
on the hope that,
مع التمني لذلك،
with the right design,
مع التصميم الصحيح،
people would be willing to overcome the stranger-danger bias.
الناس على استعداد للتغلب على التحيز ضد الغرباء،
What we didn't realize
الشيء الذي لا ندركه
is just how many people
هو كم عدد الناس
were ready and waiting to put the bias aside.
الذين استعدوا وانتظروا لوضع التحيز جانبًا.
This is a graph that shows our rate of adoption.
هذا الرسم البياني يبين معدل التكيف .
There's three things happening here.
يوجد ثلاثة أشياء تحدث هنا.
The first, an unbelievable amount of luck.
الأول، كمية لا تصدق من الحظ.
The second is the efforts of our team.
والثاني هو جهود فريق العمل لدينا.
And third is the existence of a previously unsatisfied need.
والثالث هو وجود مسبق لحاجة غير ملباة.
Now, things have been going pretty well.
الأن، الأمور أصبحت تسير بشكل جيد جدًا.
Obviously, there are times when things don't work out.
ومن الواضح هناك أوقات حين لا تسير الأمور.
Guests have thrown unauthorized parties
الضيوف ألقوا أشياء غير مصرح بها
and trashed homes.
و إهمال المنازل.
Hosts have left guests stranded in the rain.
المضيفون تركوا الزوار عالقين في المطر.
In the early days, I was customer service,
في الأيام الأولى، كنت موظف خدمة العملاء،
and those calls came right to my cell phone.
وجاءت تلك الدعوات إلى هاتفي الخلوي.
I was at the front lines of trust breaking.
كنت في الخطوط الأمامية لكسر الثقة.
And there's nothing worse than those calls,
ولايوجد شيء أسوء من تلك الإدعاءات،
it hurts to even think about them.
إنه لأمر مؤلم حتى التفكير بها.
And the disappointment in the sound of someone's voice
وخيبة الأمل في صوت شخص
was and, I would say, still is
كان وأريد القول أنه لا يزال
our single greatest motivator to keep improving.
لدينا واحدة من أعظم الحوافز للتحسن.
Thankfully, out of the 123 million nights we've ever hosted,
بفضل الله، من مجمل 123 مليون ليلة استضفناها،
less than a fraction of a percent have been problematic.
هناك أقل من جزء من المئة كانت إشكالية.
Turns out, people are justified in their trust.
واتضح لنا، أن الناس تعتمد على ثقتها.
And when trust works out right,
فعندما تسير الثقة بشكل صحيح،
it can be absolutely magical.
تكون قد سارت بشكل غاية في السحر.
We had a guest stay with a host in Uruguay,
كان لدينا ضيف أقام مع مضيف في أوروغواي،
and he suffered a heart attack.
وقال أنه تعرض لنوبة قلبية.
The host rushed him to the hospital.
المضيف نقله الى المستشفى.
They donated their own blood for his operation.
وتبرعوا بدمائهم لأجل عمليته.
Let me read you his review.
دعوني أقرأ لكم إنطباعه.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"Excellent house for sedentary travelers
منزل ممتاز للمسافرين المستقرين
prone to myocardial infarctions.
عرضة لكسور عضلة القلب.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The area is beautiful and has direct access to the best hospitals.
المنطقة ممتازة وبها طريق مباشر لأفضل المستشفىات.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Javier and Alejandra instantly become guardian angels
أليخاندرا وخافيير على الفور أصبحوا الملائكة الحارسة
who will save your life without even knowing you.
الذين سينقذون حياتك حتي بدون أن يعرفوك
They will rush you to the hospital in their own car while you're dying
سيسرعون بنقلك بسيارتهم إلى المشفى بينما تحتضر
and stay in the waiting room while the doctors give you a bypass.
وينتظرونك بينما يجري لك الطبيب جراحة قلبية
They don't want you to feel lonely, they bring you books to read.
لن يدعوك تشعر بالوحدة سيجلبون لك كتبًا لتقرأها.
And they let you stay at their house extra nights without charging you.
وسيدعونك تقيم في بيتهم ليال إضافية من دون تكلفة.
Highly recommended!"
أوصي به وبشدة!"
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Of course, not every stay is like that.
بالطبع، ليس كل القصة من هذا القبيل.
But this connection beyond the transaction
ولكن هذا التواصل ما بعد الصفقة
is exactly what the sharing economy is aiming for.
هو بالتحديد هدف التشارك الاقتصادي.
Now, when I heard that term,
الآن، عندما سمعت هذا المصطلح،
I have to admit, it tripped me up.
علي الاعتراف، لقد عرقلتني .
How do sharing and transactions go together?
فكيف نشارك ونتعامل سويًا؟
So let's be clear; it is about commerce.
لذا لنكن صريحين; إن الأمر يتعلق بالتجارة.
But if you just called it the rental economy,
ولكن إذا دعوته باقتصاد التأجير،
it would be incomplete.
ستكون غير كاملة.
The sharing economy is commerce with the promise of human connection.
مشاركة الاقتصاد هو التجارة مع وعد بالتواصل الإنساني.
People share a part of themselves,
الناس يشاركون جزء من أنفسهم،
and that changes everything.
وهذا يغير كل شيء.
You know how most travel today is, like,
أنت تعلم أكثر المسافرين اليوم، هم مثل،
I think of it like fast food --
أظن مثل الوجبة السريعة --
it's efficient and consistent,
إنها فعالة ومتسقة،
at the cost of local and authentic.
أصلية وبالتكلفة المحلية.
What if travel were like a magnificent buffet
ماذا لو كان السفر مثل بوفيه رائع
of local experiences?
خبراء محليين؟
What if anywhere you visited,
ماذا لو أي مكان ذهبت إليه،
there was a central marketplace of locals
كان هناك السوق المركزي من السكان المحليين
offering to get you thoroughly drunk
تعرض عليك حالة سكر شديدة
on a pub crawl in neighborhoods you didn't even know existed.
في ملهي ليلي بالجوار حيث لم تكن تعلم حتي بوجوده.
Or learning to cook from the chef of a five-star restaurant?
أو تعليم الطبخ من شيف بمطعم 5 نجوم؟
Today, homes are designed around the idea of privacy and separation.
اليوم، تم تصميم المنازل في جميع الأنحاء فكرة الخصوصية والانفصال.
What if homes were designed to be shared from the ground up?
ماذا لو تم تصميم المنازل حيث تكون مشتركة من الألف إلى الياء؟
What would that look like?
كيف سيكون ذلك؟
What if cities embraced a culture of sharing?
ماذا لو أحتضنت المدن ثقافة المشاركة؟
I see a future of shared cities that bring us community and connection
أنا أرى مستقبل المدن المتشاركة التي تجلب لنا الاجتماع والتواصل
instead of isolation and separation.
بدلاً من العزلة والانفصال.
In South Korea, in the city of Seoul,
في كوريا الشمالية بمدينة سيول،
they've actually even started this.
بدأوا ذلك في الحقيقة.
They've repurposed hundreds of government parking spots
اُستخدم مئاتٌ من مواقف السيارات الحكومية
to be shared by residents.
لتكون مشتركة من قبل السكان.
They're connecting students who need a place to live
هم يربطون الطلاب الذين يحتاجون مكان للإقامة
with empty-nesters who have extra rooms.
مع بيوت فارغة تضم غرف إضافية.
And they've started an incubator to help fund the next generation
وكانت قد بدأت حاضنة للمساعدة في تمويل الجيل القادم
of sharing economy start-ups.
بالشركات الناشئة عبر التشارك الاقتصادي.
Tonight, just on our service,
الليلة، فقط عبر خدماتنا،
785,000 people
785,000 شخص
in 191 countries
في 191 بلد
will either stay in a stranger's home
سيقيمون في منزل غريب
or welcome one into theirs.
أو يستضيفون أحدًا إلى منازلهم.
Clearly, it's not as crazy as we were taught.
بوضوح، ليس بهذا الجنون الذي كنا نظنه.
We didn't invent anything new.
نحن لم نخترع شيئًا جديدًا.
Hospitality has been around forever.
الاستضافة موجودة للأبد
There's been many other websites like ours.
هناك الكثير من المواقع مثلنا.
So, why did ours eventually take off?
لذا، لماذا أرتقي موقعنا بالنهاية؟
Luck and timing aside,
بوضع الحظ والتوقيت جانبًا،
I've learned that you can take the components of trust,
تعلمت أن بإمكانك أن تأخذ مكونات الثقة،
and you can design for that.
ويمكنك التصميم لذلك.
Design can overcome our most deeply rooted
التصميم يمكنه التغلب علي تحيزاتنا الأكثر تجذرًا ضد مخاطر الغرباء
And that's amazing to me.
وهذا رائع بالنسبة لي.
It blows my mind.
إنه يبهر عقلي.
I think about this every time I see a red Miata go by.
أنا أفكر بهذا في كل مرة أرى مياتا حمراء تمر بجانبي.
Now, we know design won't solve all the world's problems.
الأن، نعلم أن التصميم لن يحل كل مشاكل العالم.
But if it can help out with this one,
ولكن إذا أمكنه المساعدة بهذة،
if it can make a dent in this,
إذا كان بإمكانه التأثير بذلك،
it makes me wonder, what else can we design for next?
هذا يجعلني أتسائل، ماذا بإمكاننا تصميمه المرة القادمة
Thank you.
شكرًا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)